<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Juan Brekes on My blog</title>
    <link>https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Juan Brekes on My blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Soccer Fever</title>
      <link>https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>This will be my first participation in a Machinehack Hackathon.
For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know the terminology, the term &amp;ldquo;hackathon&amp;rdquo; is a compound word, a fusion of &amp;ldquo;hacking&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;marathon&amp;rdquo;. It aims at solving technical problems in an innovative and unconventional way in a deliberately limited period of time: in a few hours or days participants have to create usable software code, which translates into a grueling race to develop applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car Price Prediction</title>
      <link>https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>This time, I will be predicting the prices of used cars. I&amp;rsquo;ll be building 4 different Machine Learning models and Deep Learning models. In the end, I will see which one performed better.
About the data
The dataset was part of a hiring competition that was live on machinehack.com. The goal is to predict the price of a used car by knowing some of its attributes such as model, production year, category, brand, fuel type, engine volume, mileage, cylinders, color, airbags and many more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Steps for Building and Evaluating ML Models</title>
      <link>https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/articles/article-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/articles/article-2/</guid>
      <description>In this article we will briefly describe the steps to follow to build a good machine learning model. Although probably the most exciting part of the ML world is the development and testing of models, these will be of little or no use if a series of steps have not been carried out beforehand to evaluate and guarantee the quality of the information we are working with, or to check that we are really meeting the needs of the business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Data Science Interview Questions</title>
      <link>https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/articles/article-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/articles/article-1/</guid>
      <description>Harvard Business Review referred to data scientist as the &amp;ldquo;sexiest job of the 21st century.&amp;rdquo; Glassdoor ranked it the #2 job in America for 2021. It&amp;rsquo;s no wonder that in the new era of big data and machine learning, data scientists are becoming rock stars.
For this very reason, the data science field is highly competitive, and getting a first interview for those of us with little or no prior experience in the field can be very challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Card Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>As one of my first data science projects I decided to complete this traditional Kaggle competition, in which we will try to detect cases of fraud in credit card transactions.
 Sensitivity of the 4 models developed for this task   Context
Detecting fraud transactions is of great importance for any credit card company. Here we are tasked to detect potential frauds so that customers are not charged for items that they did not purchase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juanbrekes.github.io/Juan_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can contact me on any of these social media platforms
   Platform URL     Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/juan-brekes-gregoris/   Github: https://github.com/juanbrekes   Kaggle: https://www.kaggle.com/juanbrekesgregoris   Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/juan.gregoris/    Or feel free to send me an email with your questions or comments
Your Name Email Address An email address is required.  Message   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
